<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R | Stéphane Dray</title>
    <link>https://sdray.github.io/tag/r/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sdray.github.io/tag/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sdray.github.io/images/icon_hu6261ab87d1c81cb033f1e4b4983c301c_1287_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>https://sdray.github.io/tag/r/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ade4 book is now available</title>
      <link>https://sdray.github.io/post/ade4book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdray.github.io/post/ade4book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This book introduces the ade4 package for R which provides multivariate
methods for the analysis of ecological data. It is implemented around the mathematical
concept of the duality diagram, and provides a unified framework for multivariate
analysis. The authors offer a detailed presentation of the theoretical framework
of the duality diagram and also of its application to real-world ecological problems.
These two goals may seem contradictory, as they concern two separate groups of scientists,
namely statisticians and ecologists. However, statistical ecology has become a scientific
discipline of its own, and the good use of multivariate data analysis methods by
ecologists implies a fair knowledge of the mathematical properties of these methods.
The organization of the book is based on ecological questions, but these questions
correspond to particular classes of data analysis methods. The first chapters present
both usual and multiway data analysis methods. Further chapters are dedicated for
example to the analysis of spatial data, of phylogenetic structures, and of biodiversity
patterns. One chapter deals with multivariate data analysis graphs. In each chapter,
the basic mathematical definitions of the methods and the outputs of the R functions
available in ade4 are detailed in two different boxes. The text of the book itself
can be read independently from these boxes. Thus the book offers the opportunity
to find information about the ecological situation from which a question raises
alongside the mathematical properties of methods that can be applied to answer this
question, as well as the details of software outputs. Each example and all the graphs
in this book come with executable R code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
